officer, can you tell me
the way to three rivers?
about two miles to
the first main intersection,
then turn left,
it's about 60 miles.
thanks. what town is this?
suddenly.
suddenly what?
no, no, that's the name.
that's a funny name for a town.
uh-huh. hangover
from the old days.
that's the way
things used to happen here.
suddenly.
i see.
road agents,
gamblers, gunfighters.
well, i take it
things have changed.
uh-huh. things happen
so slow now,
the town council is figuring to
change the name to gradually.
thanks, officer.
pleasure. come back.
hello there, pidge.
hi, tod.
where's your mother?
we've been shopping.
i've got to put this up
in the car. want to come?
yeah, sure.
tod?
uh-huh.
well, no. i guess not.
she wouldn't let me.
who's she?
mom, of course.
well, then, you'd
better say "mom", pidge.
it's kind of not polite
to say "she" like that,
especially about your mother.
well, anyway, she wouldn't.
you know, I bet I can guess
what's on your mind.
bet you can't.
well, now, let's see.
you want an ice-cream soda?
mm, not a bad idea.
but that's not it.
you want to go to the movies?
nah, it's a war picture. mom
won't let me see war pictures.
boy, oh, boy, this is
tougher than I thought.
i got it.
you want that baseball bat.
no, but you're awful warm.
is that it?
sure, that's it!
ain't it a beauty?
but, shucks, it's no use.
mom wouldn't let me have it.
she doesn't like guns.
i know.
it's because of my father
being killed in the war.
look, pidge. if you had the gun,
what would you do with it?
stick up a filling station?
heck, no! I'd be sheriff,
and i'd catch all those road
agents and cattle rustlers,
just like you.
but what about mom?
well, I think we can
talk her into it,
what with you wanting
to be a peace officer and all.
we've got lots of time
mom's still in the market
getting groceries.
let's go.
oh, hell!
i've got it.
oh, thanks, tod. hello.
hi.
can i give you a lift up
to the house?
thanks anyway,
but i have the car with me.
going to church tomorrow?
yes.
i'll pick you up about
a quarter to 11, huh?
you never give up, do you?
ellen, i know how you feel.
believe me, i do.
and i've tried
to understand, but--
oh, i haven't asked you
to understand.
that's because
i'm in love with you.
tod, you--you
shouldn't say that to me.
well, why not? it's true.
don't, tod.
ellen, you can't go on
being a widow forever.
it's been over three years
since pete died.
don't you understand?
no one can take pete's place.
i'm not trying
to take pete's place.
i'm trying to make
a place of my own.
you've been wonderful, tod,
and i--and i'm grateful,
really i am, but--
i can't help how i feel.
ellen, you've got to stop
doing this to yourself,
because you're doing it
to pidge too, as well as to me.
you're digging a big, black pit
and shoving all of us
down into it.
leave me alone, tod, please.
pidge, where
did you get that gun?
i bought it for him, ellen.
tod, how could you?
we thought
you wouldn't mind, mom,
'cause i'm gonna be a sheriff,
just like tod.
take it off, pidge.
ellen.
i can't help it, tod.
you know i can't stand
seeing him play with a gun.
but the boy's gotta
learn sometime
that guns
aren't necessarily bad.
depends on who uses 'em.
tod carries one, doesn't he?
yes.
well, then.
just take it off, pidge.
ah, gee.
that's three dollars, please.
thank you.
ellen.
i know you don't want the boy
to see war pictures,
but it seems--
teaching children the art
of death and destruction,
the cruelties, the tortures?
ah, he's gotta know
these things exist.
then he can fight against 'em
when it's his turn.
you can't wrap the boy
in cellophane.
i can try. as long as possible.
look, when a house is on fire,
everybody has
to help put it out.
because the next time,
it might be your house.
oh, tod, don't.
church tomorrow, ellen?
no, tod, i can't go with you.
well, i can't go on asking you
and being turned down.
i mean that.
bebop! going to go over
to tilly's for a cup of java.
you can handle things,
it's a quiet day.
been a quiet day in this burg
for the last 50 years.
you?
good nightshirt!
what's the word?
get out of here!
get the sheriff,
tell him to get over here fast,
it's an emergency.
hey, take it easy, pappy.
25 mile speed limit.
where's the sheriff?
try the office.
hey, what the--
where's tod?
now, catch your breath. he--
it's an emergency. ed hawkins
has gotta see him right away.
what happened?
i don't know.
something came over the wire.
ed wouldn't even show me.
yeah, that's funny.
oh, there's tod now.
it's an emergency.
ed hawkins's gotta
see you right away. come on.
hello, ed.
thanks. get outta here.
well, wait a second.
i want to know what it's about.
top secret.
get outta here.
oh, for pete's sake,
ed, i run my pants off--
blow.
ah, shucks.
what's the word?
listen to this.
i haven't finished
typing it yet.
"sheriff tod shaw,
suddenly, california,
"confidential code hangover.
"special train number 10-19,
"carrying the president
of the united states,
"will arrive
suddenly five p.m. today.
"president will detrain and
drive to white springs ranch.
"will require adequate
transportation.
"appreciate cooperation
your staff
"with secret service operatives
arriving 1:15,
"carney, acting chief,
u.s. secret service."
no mistakes, huh?
only in typing.
five p.m.
can i use your phone?
help yourself.
uh, get me state police
headquarters at wetherby.
what's that code word again?
hangover.
hello? this is tod shaw
down in suddenly.
i want to speak
to captain aarons.
there's number 20.
the 66 crossing.
hello, cap aarons.
this is tod shaw.
say, look--
i've got a message here,
the code word is hangover.
now, i'm gonna need five of
your cars, two men to a car,
and one thompson gun
to each car, and--
oh, you did, huh? swell.
right. thanks.
they got the same message.
aarons has the show
on the road already.
gee, those state cops
don't fool around, do they?
no, they don't. say, uh--
you didn't spill this, did you?
it says "confidential".
yeah. let's just
keep it that way.
i'll run over
to kaplan's garage,
i'll be back in a minute.
ok.
hello, sheriff.
i'll be right with you.
that's not soon enough, iz.
so?
i want the big
black cadillac at 4:30.
the limousine?
yeah.
park it at the station.
backed in.
somebody getting married?
like the sheriff?
don't be funny.
this is police business.
don't tell anyone.
i don't get it.
you're not supposed to.
4:30, yeah?
no slip-ups.
mr. carney?
that's right.
my name's shaw.
get my message?
what message?
hangover.
may i see your credentials?
carney: this is wilson.
hi.
haggerty, schultz and kelly.
glad to make
your acquaintance.
yeah, i got your message.
you're a careful man, sheriff.
shaw: not always.
this seemed like
a good time to be, though.
we always have to be.
may i see your credentials?
i, uh--
i've got a limousine
ordered for 4:30.
it'll be parked right here.
carney: good.
state police have five cars
on the road from wetherby.
excellent.
shaw: i guess that's about it.
not quite.
you can still be of help to us.
we'll have to check all of
those stores facing the station.
shaw: uh, mr. carney, i know
every proprietor in this town.
you can take
my word for it.
i can't take
your word for anything.
i'm sure they're ok.
just routine.
all right, boys.
we'll park the limousine
between the tracks
when the special arrives.
pretty rough in there.
maybe.
easier to cover.
all state police cars
can go in there too.
all right.
oh, uh--
who lives up there on the hill?
pop benson, his grandson
and his daughter-in-law.
we'll check it.
mr. carney.
if there's one place in this
town doesn't need checking,
it's that one.
pop benson used to be
in the secret service himself,
before a bad ticker retired him.
pop benson?
you don't mean peter benson?
shaw: that's right.
well, i--i'll be
a monkey's uncle.
what do you mean?
oh, pete benson used
to be my old boss.
no! how do you like that, huh?
therefore, mr. shaw,
he'll be the last one
in the world to object.
pete benson,
for heaven's sake.
probably a rectifier.
probably a tube.
would you please call jud
and have him come up
and fix that thing
before you wreck it?
wreck it? wreck it?
look, i'll have you understand
i built a television transmitter
in '38, before you even
knew what television was.
yes, but did it work?
i don't know.
i never did get
to finish the receiver.
well, this is a receiver,
and i do wish you'd call jud.
i don't want to bother jud.
besides, it's time
and a half on saturday.
well, that'll be cheaper
than what it'll cost
when you get through
diddling with it.
oh, now, ellen,
stop taking it out on me
just 'cause you and tod
had a fight.
you haven't touched your cake.
don't want it.
pidge, darling, i made it
especially for you.
you made it 'cause
you wouldn't let me wear my gun.
drink your milk, darling.
sissy.
what?
that's what the guys call me.
well, i don't care
what they call you.
i'm your mother, and i think
i know what's best for you.
pidge!
pidge, you shouldn't walk out
when i'm talking to you.
i thought you were finished.
the boy's just disappointed,
that's all, ellen.
dad,
please stop interfering.
first you cancel him out
on the hike with cub scouts,
then the next thing--
pidge. go to your room.
i'll have this old set
perking in a minute, son,
you and me watch the ball game.
dad, i've had this
for the last time.
ellen, you're a grown-up girl.
you got a problem
you haven't worked out.
that's no reason why pidge
should have your problem.
i've only done what
i thought was right, dad.
i read about an experiment once.
kept germs away from a kid.
raised him pure
and scientifically.
first time he got out
in the rough,
he caught cold
and died of pneumonia.
what does that have
to do with pidge?
the kid hadn't been exposed.
he had no immunity.
there's cruelty and hatred
and tyranny in the world.
you can't make believe
they aren't there.
and pidge has got to learn
what is the law
and what isn't the law,
so's he can defend it.
defend it?
so he can become a soldier
and go out and be murdered,
like his father was?
my son was killed in the
performance of his duty, ellen.
duty! being blown to bits
on some godforsaken battlefield,
thousands of miles
from where he was born.
you call that duty?
yes, ellen.
well, is that what
you'd like for pidge?
would that make you happy?
if pete could hear you now,
i think he'd be ashamed of you.
how can you say
a terrible thing like that?
when the old boys
wrote those words,
"life, liberty
and the pursuit of happiness,"
they sounded mighty nice.
but they wouldn't
have been worth a plug nickel
if somebody
hadn't made 'em stick.
pidge: grandpa!
grandpa! grandpa!
the window!
look out the window!
golly!
what is it?
coming down the mountain
from wetherby!
a whole raft of state troopers!
see 'em?
she'll cut it fine.
you couldn't possibly
be surprised,
with all those sirens blasting.
i try to beat 'em.
state troopers.
right on time.
oh, they're good.
the best.
all right, bart, follow me.
ok.
well, there are two routes
to the white springs ranch.
you can go over
the mountains here,
or you can drop down
to the main highway,
go on into three rivers,
and the ranch is
about 20 miles farther on.
we'll stick to
the main highway.
too much chance of an ambush
in those mountains.
yes, haggerty?
we could use a roof watch
on those stores, chief,
beside the street check.
look, mr. carney. every
proprietor in this town
has been here
at least five years.
i know them, i know their kids.
ah, it isn't that, sheriff.
it's the stranger that might use
one of those stores for cover.
i'd like them to lock up
at ten minutes to five,
stay locked up until
ten minutes after five.
oh, and, uh, put a man
on the roof, too.
all right, burg.
give 'em the word.
no one, including
the proprietors,
are to remain in those stores
at locking time.
anyone seen inside
after ten minutes to five
might be shot on sight.
like the man says,
it's important.
yes, sir.
tell wilson to keep
the station clear.
schultz'll take over troopers
and block off traffic approaches
from 4:30 on.
right. and there's
another hazard, sir.
a house, up on the hill.
yeah, i know.
i'll check that one myself.
yes, sir.
tod, what the hades
is going on in this burg?
did some galoot
make a uranium strike?
nah, not exactly.
now look, slim,
you take over here
and i'll catch up
with you later.
from 4:30 on, i want
all pedestrian traffic
kept off main street
between oak and alder.
the state boys'll help you.
if anybody in town squawks,
why, you smooth things over.
they know you, and this is all
going to seem
a little strange to them.
i'm confused myself.
never have seen so many cops.
what goes on?
ah, this is mr. carney,
special agent in the treasury
department. secret service.
mr. carney, slim adams,
one of my deputies.
how do you do?
secret service?
i get it.
they're shipping the national
debt through here in gold bars.
just don't worry about it.
you'll find out later.
all right, come on. let's go
and check that car you hired.
bang! got him out.
buffalo bill, you'd better
put that gun away
before your mom sees it
or she'll tan your hide.
oh, dad, i do wish
you'd call jud
and let him come up
and fix that.
shucks, ellen. i knew ohm's law
before they even passed it.
well, i don't want pidge
to miss the ball game,
after missing the movie
and everything.
all right, boy. come on,
get ready to plug this set in
while i hold this screw down,
we'll see what happens.
ok.
dad, are you sure
you know what you're doing?
ellen, please.
i know, but it says
on the back of that
that there're 5,000 volts,
and that's dangerous.
ellen, will you please
stop being a woman?
ready, boy? plug in.
dad! dad,
are you all right?
well, i guess i'm all right.
it just scared the pants off me,
that's all.
golly! look at this!
i guess maybe
you'd better call jud, huh?
oh, honestly.
that was a close call, boy.
how much is 5,000 volts?
enough.
to kill you?
well, it'd probably pick you up
and toss you across the room.
that is, unless you were
standing in a puddle of water,
and then you'd be grounded.
and if you were grounded, it'd
kill you deader than a doornail.
would it hurt?
like blazes!
you stay away
from that set, now,
and stay away
from those wall plugs.
don't monkey with electricity
unless you know
what you're doing.
why did you, grandpa?
you got me there, boy.
i'll get it.
jud says he'll be up
in a little while.
i'm sorry.
honestly!
yes?
mrs. benson?
that's right.
is your husband at home?
my hus--no, i'm a widow.
what i should have asked was,
are you the owner of this house?
well, no, i'm not, it belongs
to my father-in-law.
what is it you want?
i'm john baron, special agent.
federal bureau of investigation.
these are my men.
do you suppose i could have
a few words with mr. benson?
well, just a moment.
won't you come in?
dad!
oh, how are you, gents?
john baron, special agent.
for heaven's sake! f.b.i.
may we come in?
why, sure, sure!
come right in. come right in.
make yourselves at home.
thanks.
not at all.
i get quite a kick out of this.
used to be with the treasury
department myself.
really?
back in the old days.
collector of
internal revenue, eh?
tax collector? not on your life.
secret service.
you don't say.
grandpa was president coolidge's
bodyguard.
you don't say.
yep. back in 1928.
youngest retirement
in the service.
account of my heart. not
heart trouble, you understand.
an accident on
one of cal's fishing trips.
a hunter.
got the slug right here.
say, that's a nasty one.
how come you're still alive?
pop: i don't know.
lodged in my heart.
they took it out. had to take it
easy, so they retired me.
man: you're lucky.
luckier still
if it hadn't hit me.
i want to be in
the secret service someday.
thought you was going
to be a sheriff like tod.
squirts like you are supposed
to grow up and be president.
name's pidge, mr. baron.
glad to meet you, pidge.
i ain't a squirt.
mr. baron, what did
you want to see us about?
is something wrong?
nothing wrong yet, mrs. benson.
but there might be.
we're just checking.
on us?
on the house.
do you mind if we have
a look around?
help yourself,
but what i want to know--
we're going to have
a look around
with or without your permission,
mr. benson.
it's an emergency.
check it.
there must be
something the matter.
anyone else live here,
besides you three?
ellen: no.
anyone been by here today?
just the usual routine.
willy harris left the milk.
what's this all about,
mr. baron?
just being careful.
i'll explain later.
two bedrooms,
one bathroom. all clear.
one here. just like they said.
kitchen, back pantry,
back door,
stairs go downhill
to garage under kitchen.
cellar door in hall. clear.
car in the garage.
look at this for a set-up.
i'm sorry, folks, but i'm afraid
we're going to have
to hang around for a while.
why?
what's the matter?
don't be alarmed.
there's nothing wrong.
well, course
there's something wrong.
the f.b.i. doesn't pay us
a visit for the heck of it.
well, i won't stay.
i'll take pidge and go--
no, ma'am.
nobody leaves the house
until we do.
why not? what's happened?
look, just go about
your business
like it was any other
saturday afternoon.
read your papers
and look at your t.v.
anything you want.
but nobody leaves the house.
something fishy about all this.
it's official business.
what sort of official business?
mr. benson.
as a former agent
of the secret service,
you should understand.
either i'm getting
old and stupid,
or else i'm--
at five p.m. this afternoon,
the president of the united
states arrives in town
on a special.
what?
golly!
the president?
well, that's different.
do you mean to say
the president's
going to get off the train here?
that's right.
golly, gramps.
we gotta go down and see it,
we just gotta.
the president! why,
that's the greatest thing
ever happened to this town!
can we go down and see it,
gramps? can we?
sorry, kid. no.
benny, bring in the gear.
put the car out back.
bart, you see
the back door's locked tight
and check the cellar to be sure.
i still don't understand--
mr. benson.
it should be obvious
to you that
if anybody wanted
to kill the president,
he could do
a beautiful job of it
right from this window of yours.
for the love of mike!
that may be true,
but you don't think
that ellie and me--
of course not.
but we have to remain here
to protect you
and the president
from somebody else who might.
oh.
carney.
yeah.
uh, is this all routine?
it seems to me
to be kind of overboard.
i mean, all this checking
and everything,
as though
you expected this town to--
sheriff. have you noticed
any strangers in town
during the past week?
no.
are you sure?
sure i'm sure.
i know everybody in this burg.
the only strangers
we get are tourists,
you know,
and we get 'em all the time,
stopping for gas,
a bite to eat, that's all.
we want to know from
either you or your deputies
the minute any stranger
doesn't keep going through.
then this isn't routine.
no, it isn't.
can you tell me?
the los angeles police picked up
a small-time stool pigeon
night before last.
shot through the lungs
and left for dead.
smiley bitters. before he died,
he told them something was up.
what do you mean,
something was up?
an assassination attempt.
well, can you believe that?
in our business,
we can't afford not to.
i mean, the tip
of a dying stool pigeon.
the stoolie seemed
very proud of being an american,
before he kicked off.
meaning crime is crime, but
this is something else again?
right. so, we can't take
any chances. let's go.
can we see the president,
grandpa?
mm-mm.
can we, mom?
no, pidge, we have to stay here.
you can watch him from here.
but i wanna get up close.
well, use your telescope, boy.
bring him right up to your eye.
aww!
sorry, pidge. no dice.
back door locked. how about
the phone in the kitchen?
want me to yank it?
no, we don't change the pattern
at all. give benny a hand.
mr. baron, uh, something
i don't understand.
i was in the service myself--
so you told me.
and though we made
every precautionary check,
we never went
to extremes like this unless--
unless you were tipped that
there was to be
an attempted assassination.
well, you don't mean it.
i mean it.
but you're f.b.i.
secret service is responsible
for the safety of the president.
we're using everybody this trip,
mr. benson.
have a look down there.
state troopers, your local law
enforcement agencies and us.
you don't know if old dan carney
is down there, do you?
he and i worked together
in the old days.
he's chief of
the presidential staff now.
that's confidential
information.
this is a terrible thing.
not your worry, mr. benson.
of course it's my worry.
i'm an american, ain't i?
it's everybody's worry.
car. somebody's driving up
to the house.
who is it?
pidge: it's tod!
ellen: he's the sheriff,
mr. baron.
there's someone with him.
who's with him?
well, i don't know.
i've never seen him before.
well, for the love of mike!
what?
well, if it isn't
old dan carney!
gray as an old shirt
and red in the face as ever.
hi, pop. got an old friend
of yours here.
dan, you dirty old irishman!
dan carney.
oh, pop, how are you?
it's grand to see you.
hey, why aren't you dead?
old buzzards like me
live forever.
hey, old hawkeye,
you're getting bald.
now, just what do you expect
after 25 years?
ah, ha-ha-ha! come on in.
sure.
come on in,
make yourself at home.
this is my daughter-in-law.
how do you do?
hello.
this is my grandson pidge.
hiya, pidge.
pidge, this is mr. carney.
secret service.
he guards the president.
like mr. baron?
who?
baron.
oh, you didn't know.
your boys got here ahead of you.
sheriff!
one sound from the kid, pop,
and he's dead.
the train muffled it.
get rid of him.
put him in the cellar.
and you'd better take the rug
with you, it's a giveaway.
you get the message, brave boy?
mom! mom!
pidge. now, you gotta be still.
no noise.
you stink!
pidge, shut up.
guts.
he's only eight.
lotsa guts.
mom! mom!
no trouble with you,
you're all busted up.
all right. take care of her.
you've got it, now,
let's be practical.
i don't want any more shooting
around here.
i want it nice
and quiet and cozy.
now get her up and bring
her around and explain to her
that one phony and she's got
a kid with his throat cut.
doesn't make
much noise that way.
the same goes for you, too.
anybody steps outta line,
the boy.
that's simple enough.
ellen.
ellen, listen to me.
ellen! pay attention.
now, listen to me
and don't look like that.
everybody is all right.
you've got to get
ahold of yourself.
no matter what happens,
you've got to hang on.
if you scream,
or make one false move,
he'll murder the boy.
you understand?
he'll murder pidge!
do you hear him, lady?
yes. yes.
good. then we're all in accord.
all right, all right. inside.
we've got a long time to wait.
relax.
move the kitchen table
in front of the window.
all right, sit down, sit down.
look at your t.v.
it ain't workin'.
well, work him over, then.
fix him up. don't sit there
waiting to blow your cork.
keep yourselves occupied.
i gotta think.
tod. tod, are you badly hurt?
pop: bullet hit the bone, broke
it, i guess. he's bled a lot.
we need a doctor.
look at his face.
tell her, pop.
you're the doctor, ellen.
we can't have no doctor.
we can't set a broken arm.
tough.
can you?
baron: me?
straighten this fracture?
you couldn't take it.
you straighten it.
hold on, brave boy.
tie it up.
may we take him
into the bedroom?
sure. but the boy stays here.
and leave the door open.
all right, let's go to work.
pop, we got to do something.
well, i know, i know,
but what? what?
they've got pidge.
oh, none of us count.
not even pidge.
we haven't got a chance.
as long as we're alive,
we got a chance.
we got to find
a flaw in his plan.
we'll think of something.
pop. haven't you got a gun?
a gun?
yeah, right in the drawer.
my gun.
is it loaded?
no.
tod!
i hid the cartridges
on account of pidge.
you're a dirty, lousy gangster!
why, you--
leave him alone, benny.
did you hear what he said?
yeah, i heard what he said.
he's been looking
at too much television.
he ain't a bad squirt.
just tell him to shut up.
sure, sure.
this thing's metal.
steel top, chrome legs.
i figured wood.
no difference. use the brackets.
screw 'em to the leg
and then to the floor.
that way, the table won't dance.
you're a coward!
you're a bunch of cowards!
and you're gettin' too fresh.
so button it.
johnny, why all the trouble?
big deal. this is a lot of work.
do it, benny.
but, johnny, i don't see why--
i said just do it, benny!
once you get the gun anchored,
you got a solid base.
you'll see when we get to it.
this gun's got a heavy recoil,
it won't stand still.
and we got just three seconds
to nail the president.
and i don't want the table
to shimmy when we get to it.
ah, a tommy gun
would do just as good.
tommy gun stinks.
no accuracy, no punch.
might as well use a revolver.
this is the gun.
when i was in the army--
so i wasn't in the army.
tighter, tighter.
pop. you find
those cartridges yet?
not yet.
this is quite a gun, benny.
quite a gun.
i did a lot of chopping in
the war with a baby like this.
a lot of chopping.
you're wrong about me, pidge.
being a coward.
last war, i got a silver star.
north of cassino.
pocket of resistance.
i killed 27 men, all by myself.
i won a silver star, a medal.
ah, you stole it.
they're hurting pidge.
all right, take it easy.
take it easy.
get up. stay there!
johnny, take it easy.
johnny, relax.
for the love of mike,
what's a silver star?
i won it.
ok, johnny.
ok, you won it.
i got 'em.
they've been there a long time.
yeah. get 'em back in here.
what are you all tryin' to pull?
all of you, inside.
come on, come on.
feeling better?
yeah.
you're lucky.
he didn't mean to wing you,
he meant to blow
your brains out.
then he's a bad shot.
yeah, but i'm not.
so maybe you'd better sit down
and stay there.
that way'll be safer
for everybody.
you got that duty look
in your eye.
i've seen it up on the line.
the line? you up on the line?
some other time. down.
bart, you fool!
bart: what? what?
his car's out front.
put it in the garage, quick.
i have to think of everything.
oh, great. just great.
might as well advertise.
that was a close one.
hot in here.
see what time it is?
all right, suppose you tell me
what happens in this house
on a saturday afternoon between
four and five.
pattern.
smart guy.
sure. and we don't
break that pattern.
we're here for a reason,
and if we break it,
we might blow the deal,
you know?
mario slings the paper over
the fence around 4:30 or so.
delivery boy. does he come in?
anyone else?
cy hamill went up the mountain
huntin' jackrabbits.
he'll be by on his way back.
will he stop?
not unless he's got
something to brag about.
anybody else?
nobody.
anybody know that you and the
other guy were comin' up here?
that's an interesting question.
what's the interesting answer?
you guess.
tell him, tod.
sheriff, if you think i have any
qualms about killing this kid,
you couldn't be more wrong.
the thing about killing him
or you or her or him
is that i wouldn't be
gettin' paid for it.
and i don't like givin' anything
away for free.
shaw: neither do i.
including information.
your guts are showin'
all over the place, brave boy.
no, no. not me. i'm scared.
you see, the way i figure it,
baron, i'm a dead man anyway.
so's the boy,
so's ellen, so's pop.
it's just a question
of now or later.
and if it gives the president
a bit of an edge,
why, then, we get it now.
they won't hurt us. they won't
hurt pidge. he said so.
because it's convenient, ellen.
you think these crims would kill
the president and then take off,
leavin' us behind
to identify them?
you said you wouldn't
hurt pidge.
sure, sure. and i meant it.
don't listen to this guy.
he's just being brave
with your kid's life.
i knew guys like that
in the army.
we're just doing a job,
that's all.
identifying us is not involved.
by seven o'clock tonight,
we'll be out of the country
and you'll never see us again.
tell him, tod, tell him.
never mind, lady.
we'll just assume that
they knew he was coming up here.
so that if somebody else
comes up to check on 'im,
you can tell 'em the sheriff
and his friend were here,
but they had to go
someplace else.
that's all.
i have to go to the bathroom.
go with him, bart.
i don't need any help.
come on, come on.
ok. table's screwed down.
all right.
get the tripod up there
and drill a hole in each leg,
bolt the tripod to the table,
put it center
in front of the window.
i thought i told you
to sit down.
just stretching my legs.
you're a very careful man.
that's right.
plan on everything, huh?
sheriff, the first man they
shoot to the moon in a rocket
will take pains too, 'cause
that's never been done before.
neither has this.
doesn't that worry you?
haven't got time to worry.
i just make my plans
and carry 'em out.
that's what john wilkes booth
thought, too.
booth? hah!
i'm no actor, bustin' my leg
on a stage
so i can yell,
"down with the tyrants!"
if booth wasn't such a ham,
he might've made it.
he got pretty far at that,
though.
the guy who killed garfield
didn't make it either.
him? huh.
he didn't plan anything.
just took a lucky shot, strictly
left-handed, just like mckinley.
and zangara got the chair
for his try at roosevelt.
he had to try it in a crowd.
i hate crowds.
so nobody ever made it.
up till here.
i'm just a guy makin' a livin'.
and i think you've stretched
long enough.
as you were.
bart, take over benny's work.
ok.
benny.
yeah, johnny.
go downtown,
see what's going on down there,
especially the station plan.
leave the car here.
why me?
because wheeler can fly a plane
and you can't.
oh, but me,
i'm expendable, huh?
no, i just don't want anything
to happen to wheeler.
well, why can't i
take the car?
because if they nail you, benny,
we need the car
to get to the plane.
johnny, that place
is crawling with cop--
you're gettin' paid, ain't you?
yeah.
you can't say
you ain't gettin' enough.
i'll be back.
bart: johnny.
look. nice and steady,
just like you wanted it.
open the curtain.
a trap.
a big, beautiful booby trap.
you can't do this.
you can't do it.
you're wrong, lady.
take a look.
go on. take a look.
i can do it
and i'm going to do it.
but you're an american citizen.
sure. and at
one minute after five,
i'm going to be
a very rich american citizen.
you'll never get away with it.
shut up.
i got a stomachache.
take a pill.
maybe the old man's right,
johnny.
it's a terrible thing.
a terrible thing.
turn it off, will you?
it's just another man.
a man!
but the president--
yeah. yeah, i never killed
a president before.
who's that?
shaw: it's jud kelly.
pop: television set
went on the blink.
ellen sent for him
to come and fix it
so the boy could watch
the ball game.
why didn't you tell me?
well, we simply forgot,
that's all.
he's a harmless boy, baron.
don't hurt him.
ok. but if you cross me, i--
he won't. he won't.
all right, pop.
you got the ball.
let him in, but watch it.
ellen, we got to keep
this man talking.
why?
why, because
that's his weakness.
sooner or later,
he'll drop his guard.
we've got to find a way
to get pop's gun.
hi, pop. what's new?
hello, jud.
figured i'd better get up
and fix your rig
before you
electrocuted yourself.
come on in.
tod! what happened to you?
ask him.
the same thing'll happen to you,
unless you do
exactly as you're told.
you're kiddin'.
is that real?
it's real, all right.
what's your name?
jud kelly.
what are you doin' here?
i came to fix
the television set.
drop it.
all right, bart, case him.
i don't have any dough,
if that's what you want.
what is this? a--a stick-up?
yeah, that's right.
it's a stick-up.
you'll never get away with it.
go over and sit down, buster.
take your luggage with you.
you too. down.
i don't dig it.
did they rob the bank?
what's the gun for?
what's going on?
where's your store?
main street.
who runs it?
just me.
all alone?
do you have to point
that gun at me?
alone?
answer him.
yeah.
you locked up when you left?
nobody knows
you were coming here?
that's right.
just a service call.
that gun makes me nervous,
mister.
i'm not gonna be a hero.
you can put the gun away.
sure. but i'm telling you,
buster, like the others.
one pass and the kid gets it.
that's right.
he gets it.
so, you see, his life
depends on you. got it?
yeah.
wilson? carney back yet?
no. he's certainly
been gone a long time.
maybe we oughta load the gun
now, to be sure, huh?
no. that's just what
the sheriff would like.
forget about me. i've had it.
don't con me, sheriff.
the minute this gun was loaded,
one of you brave boys
might decide to go for the ride,
just to fire it.
and if you fired it, that might
alert a few
state cops down there,
and the game would be over,
wouldn't it?
you got any food in the house?
of course i have.
i'm going to grab a bite, bart.
watch 'em.
bring me a little glass of milk,
will you, johnny?
my ulcer's murdering me.
just watch 'em, bart.
watch 'em!
i don't dig it. would somebody
tell me what's going on?
sit down. be quiet.
haven't you any feelings
at all?
no, i haven't, lady.
they were taken out of me
by experts.
feeling's a trap.
show me a guy with feelings
and i'll show you a sucker.
it's a weakness. makes you think
of something besides yourself.
if i had any feelings left in me
at all, they'd be for me.
just me.
don't you ever think
of your mother? your father?
think of 'em? humph!
i used to think of 'em
a great deal.
my mother wasn't married.
my old man was a dipso.
they left me in a home. a home!
you stink!
johnny!
pop: pidge, come back here!
the kid.
hold it.
pidge! pidge!
get 'im.
stick 'em up or i'll blast you.
nice goin', bart.
it's only a cap pistol.
i gave it to him myself.
don't you touch her, darn you.
i oughta beat his brains out,
the little--
what's so funny?
you should have seen your face.
a cap pistol!
go ahead. laugh yourself sick.
that's a pretty good model,
though, ain't it?
they make 'em real today,
don't they?
here you are, pidge.
blow his brains out.
couple of big bold bad men
gettin' scared to death
by a six-bit cap pistol.
i oughta beat that kid.
i'm not sure that
he couldn't take you.
go put some milk on your ulcer
and bring me a piece
of the cake.
yeah, i need some milk.
pain's pretty bad.
where's benny?
why don't we hear from benny?
sit.
if this isn't a stick-up,
what is it?
did you come up here
to fix a television set, junior?
yeah.
well, then, fix
the television set.
tod, what's going on?
they're planning to
assassinate the president, jud.
which president?
the president
of the united states.
he arrives here this afternoon.
you're kidding.
no. no, you're not kidding.
the president?
kill the president?
they can't. they couldn't
do a thing like that.
they're stinking traitors.
they're benedict arnolds.
are you guys crazy?
you can't do a thing like that.
baron: sit down, reckless.
don't you realize
what that means?
that's assassination.
he's your president too.
make a deal with you, boy.
we kill you
instead of the president.
that's even steven. ok with you?
thought not.
anybody else wanna take the heat
off the president?
how about you, sheriff?
it's a bad joke, baron.
anybody else wanna volunteer?
they're commies.
they're enemy agents!
all right,
who is behind it, baron?
i haven't the slightest idea.
what's in it for you?
you're curious,
aren't you, sheriff?
while i last.
i like you, sheriff.
you've got guts.
you must've been a good soldier.
i got by.
i won a silver star.
that's pretty good.
i killed 27 jerries
all by myself.
you're a born killer,
that's all.
yeah.
some guys liked it.
i know a couple.
hard to match up,
isn't it, baron?
just when you get real good at
something, you're a murderer.
yeah.
over there, you can knock over
a whole platoon.
or a guy invents a bomb
and kills 100,000 people
just like that,
and maybe gets more medals.
here, you put a slug in
a double-crossing squirt
that isn't even worth burying
and you have to take the gas.
ah, why do you hate
the president so?
i got no feeling
against the president.
i'm just earning a living.
by treason.
ace-deuce craps. don't
give me that politics jazz.
it's not my racket. i don't even
know who's paying me.
and i don't want to know.
what's the difference?
didn't it occur to you
why they want you to do it?
certainly it did.
but that makes them suckers,
not me.
i'm the guy
who's gettin' it made.
listen, sheriff. a man can stand
for so much and no more.
why, before the war,
i drifted and grifted and ran.
always lost
in the great big crowd.
i hated that crowd.
i used to dream about the crowd,
once in a while.
i used to see all those faces,
scratchin'
and shovin' and bitin'.
and then the mist would clear
and somehow,
all those faces would be me.
all me, and all nothin'.
but the war changed
everything, eh, baron?
i'm no traitor, sheriff.
i won a silver star.
and learned how to kill.
yeah.
maybe i did.
maybe that changed everything.
maybe people began
to know who i was.
after the show, i hooked up with
an outfit for good dough.
the finger said
where and how much,
and johnny baron did the job.
do you think anybody else
could handle this job?
do you think benny wheeler could
do it without me?
you're talking too much, johnny.
there's nobody else
can do this job,
because they got
too much feeling.
and feeling's no good.
i got nothing against
the president, sheriff.
he's just worth
a half a million bucks to me.
tax free.
makin' my own laws
about the taxes too, pop.
the guy is goofy.
shut up, jud.
listen to him, buster.
and don't ever say that again.
ever!
you heard him, jud.
a half a million dollars, huh?
yeah. that's a lot of scratch,
sheriff.
a man could retire
on that amount of scratch.
how do you know
it'll ever be paid?
half of it's been paid.
and the rest?
i'll get it.
i wouldn't be sure.
it's not just a man.
it's the president.
that's what's so funny.
the laugh is on the guys
who are paying the freight.
all this loot, and they don't
even know what they're doing.
a half a million clams,
for absolutely nothing.
because tonight,
at five o'clock,
i kill the president,
and one second after five,
there's a new president.
what changes?
nothin'.
what are they payin' for?
otherwise, i wouldn't have
taken the job, sheriff.
you'd have taken it.
you think so?
yeah.
why?
all right, take it easy.
come on, lady.
do as you're told,
and everything will be fine.
answer straight,
clean and plain.
answer it.
hello?
benny: mrs. benson,
let me speak to the chief.
benny?
yeah. train's on time.
the car will be waiting in front
of the station like you figured,
facing you.
fine. get back as soon as
you can and don't be followed.
benny: check.
there's the big boy's car now.
lovely target.
hey, hold it, mister.
yes, officer? what is it?
what's your name?
fred. fred whittaker.
what are you doing in town?
just passing through.
where's your car?
i don't have one. i hitchhiked
in from three rivers.
waiting for the train out,
figured i'd take
the train out to l.a.
what train?
the five o'clock.
the five o'clock?
now, that's right strange.
why, officer?
because we don't have
any five o'clock train
that stops here, mister,
except today.
and that happens
to be a special
that you don't know about.
except that you do.
must be some mistake.
you made it.
oh, now, look, officer.
i--i got identification.
i can prove who i am. i've got
my driver's license right here.
come on.
gunfire!
hold it! don't shoot him!
i told you not to kill him.
not to kill him? after he--
he was our only link.
come on.
so long, benny.
do you think they got him?
i only hope he's dead.
haggerty?
yes, sir.
we got him.
dead, unfortunately.
wasn't carney's last checkpoint
the house on the hill?
haggerty: that's right,
but he and the sheriff
were going to check the white
springs ranch route too.
we haven't been able
to reach them.
well, take two troopers
and backtrack 'em.
start with
the house on the hill.
we've got to find carney.
haggerty: right.
now, we got trouble.
everybody except mrs. benson,
down in the cellar.
what are you going to do?
nothing, i hope. move.
anybody gets brave,
kill 'em all.
you can only hang once.
pidge, stay up there.
now look,
get a grip on yourself.
i want you to look relaxed.
if you don't pull this off,
everybody is dead,
do you understand?
all of us. dead. so be yourself.
i don't know what you mean.
they'll come up here to check
whether carney
and the sheriff were here,
and i want you to go out front.
i don't want 'em in the house.
i can't, i don't know how,
i don't know what to say.
just go out
and water the flowers.
do anything you like,
but keep busy.
lipstick and rouge, quick.
now listen to me carefully.
they'll come up to check
whether carney
and the sheriff were here,
certainly they were here.
they came up to check the house.
but at three o'clock,
they left here.
they went out on
the white springs ranch road.
they took pop
and the kid with them.
and that's the last
you saw of them, you got it?
you got it?
yes, yes!
you look like a ghost.
step on it.
pull it off, lady,
or everybody is dead.
everybody.
he's getting rattled, pop.
how do you mean?
he didn't expect benny
to get shot.
got anything in mind?
maybe. now, listen--
bart: shut up, you guys.
mrs. benson?
yes.
my name's haggerty.
then you must be
one of mr. carney's men.
that's right. has he been here?
ellen: i haven't seen them
since they left.
they--they came up here
about three o'clock
to check the house, they said.
i--i don't know why.
who is they?
why, mr. carney
and sheriff shaw.
then they said they had to check
the white springs ranch road.
is your father-in-law,
mr. benson, here?
well, no.
no, he isn't.
you see, he used to be
mr. carney's chief.
haggerty: yes, i know.
so mr. carney took him along.
my little boy too.
haggerty: then you're alone?
yes.
and you haven't heard from them
since they left?
no, no, i haven't.
something's wrong,
i know something's wrong.
no, no, mrs. benson.
nothing's wrong.
we're, uh--we're just checking,
that's all.
but if you see or hear
from them before i do,
please have them
check the detail
down at the railroad station.
it's very important. thanks.
all right, lady. inside.
come on, come on.
very nice. very nice job.
congratulations.
you don't like me, do you?
you're an animal.
i don't like you either.
animals kill each other to
live, that's what you're doing.
how do you like
your roast beef?
medium rare or well done?
all right, bart,
run 'em in, it's clear.
i wish you were dead.
you haven't got the guts.
just give me a chance.
there's your chance.
go ahead, take it.
but remember
the squirt in the cellar.
that's right.
think of the president first.
let's not think of ourselves.
i didn't give you
a whole chance.
but you didn't even take
a half a chance.
everything ok, johnny?
sure, everything's fine.
she played her part real good.
should be on television.
you! didn't i tell you
to fix the television set?
you told me to sit.
get your stuff and fix it. it'll
keep you from gettin' patriotic.
i don't do something, i'll blow
my top just sittin' here.
fix the set
and shut your mouth.
i don't like what you say
anyway.
now fix it.
we've still got time.
all yours.
open 'em.
about 200 yards.
shaw: baron, isn't that
a german rifle?
yeah. you know it?
i know it. where were you
during the war?
all the way
from the kasserine pass.
i won a silver star.
where were you?
normandy to the elbe,
by way of the bulge.
you get up into germany?
no. bet you were one
of those big-shot guys, huh?
with the gold bar
on the shoulder.
no, no, i was a corporal.
how about you?
corporal? i made sergeant.
you didn't like officers.
officers. big shots.
yes, sir. no, sir. salute, sir.
big shots.
and you don't like big shots.
not when you're bigger,
sheriff.
i killed more jerries than
any five officers put together.
i did some pretty good choppi''
in the war. pretty good.
like i said before, you're
a born killer, that's all.
yeah. they taught me how
and i liked it.
hah! my c.o. used to stand there
and shake like a leaf
while i chopped.
if more guys like me
had command--
tell me one thing, baron.
how come you missed germany?
they sent me home.
my tour was finished.
your tour? in the infantry?
are you kiddin'?
why, you finish your tour
in the infantry
when they plant you in a box.
tour! that was for
the air corps.
turn it off.
yeah.
you probably went over the hill.
i said turn it off.
you know, baron,
you got the yard look.
you look yardbird to me.
i'm telling you, sheriff,
turn it off.
big shot with the yardbirds,
huh? come on, now, tell me.
where were you court-martialed?
what was it for? rape?
nah, nah. not rape.
killin', that's what
you like. killin'.
maybe shooting down
unarmed p.w.s, huh?
sit down and shut up.
ah, but, by golly,
you got away with it, so--
i got it. section eight.
you went out on a section eight.
section eight. psycho
in charge of killin', huh?
you know, i knew guys like you.
killin' was sweet. rather
kill a man than love a girl.
a real kick.
the thrill with the guts.
stop it, tod! stop it!
or maybe you didn't like
your c.o.
maybe you shot him in the back.
that it?
maybe you kill--aaargh!
like i said, shut up.
tod. tod, darling,
it's hopeless.
it's not five o'clock yet.
going to keep your trap shut?
yeah.
hurts, huh?
it hurts.
well, i can keep kicking as long
as you keep shootin'
your face off.
i know.
jud: pop, you were right.
you blew the power tube.
i have one here.
i'll have her perking
in a second.
you know, i was thinking, jud,
if you were to clamp
the main plate lead
to a good ground
like that table there,
we'd get a better picture.
lot of lines in it now.
clamp the main plate lead
to the table.
cut the static lines.
expert. first he wrecks the set,
then he tells the kid
how to fix it.
main plate lead?
yeah.
that's right, jud. all it needs
is a higher potential ground.
we're a long way from
the broadcasting station.
what are you guys yappin' about?
pop: technical talk, mister.
i'm an old radioman.
battleship new york,
world war i.
gramps beat the germans
single-handed .
not exactly, son, but i was
there at scapa flow
when the german fleet
surrendered.
all right, all right,
stop the bullin'.
and fix that set, will you?
yes, sir.
oh!
dad! dad, what is it?
pain, bad.
baron: what hit him?
it's his heart.
he has a bad heart.
pidge, my pills.
top drawer of the bureau.
i'll get 'em.
you stay put.
the kid'll get 'em.
pidge, put down that gun
and get some water
for your grandfather.
but, mom, listen.
you heard me, pidge.
aww, gee.
you know what i think, pop?
i got a feeling your heart
attack's a phony.
pain's bad.
i'm warnin', if you're
tryin' to pull something,
you'd better watch it.
baron, i've been thinkin'.
you've been thinkin' you'd like
to take a crack at this rifle.
you think i want
to get myself killed?
yes. frankly, sheriff,
i don't think you'd mind
gettin' yourself killed.
shaw: nobody wants to die.
baron: do we have to talk about
it? why don't you shut up?
shaw: no guts.
baron: nerves, that's all.
it gets on my nerves.
shaw: now, why would i want
to get myself killed?
baron: because it's
five minutes to five,
and a shot might bring
those state troopers
stormin' all over the joint
before the president arrives.
but, sheriff, i can put you away
in two seconds
by twisting your arm again.
that way, there's no noise.
so don't go winnin'
any postmortem medals.
i wouldn't enjoy winnin'
a postmortem medal
any more than you're going
to enjoy that postmortem money.
what'd you say?
what'd he say?
i said nobody ever made it.
and you won't either.
you don't think so?
so you got a plane.
you'll never reach it
ahead of the police.
and if you do, you'll never
make it to the border.
you ever hear
of the jet fighter?
you know how many
airstrips there are
between here and the border?
you know, a fella
could get an education
just listenin' to this guy.
well, maybe he's right, johnny.
look.
you said half the money
had already been paid.
a smart guy would
hit the road right now.
fly outta here.
skip the president.
spend the money
in south america. alive.
he's right, johnny.
why take the risk?
we can lam now, we can make it.
we don't have
to fool with this thing.
it's too big, johnny. there's
something wrong with it.
chicken.
chicken?
all right, so call it chicken.
who wants to be rich and dead?
they'll get us. they
never missed yet, johnny.
they guy's right.
you've got the loot.
let's take off
and get outta here for good.
once we're across the border--
ace-deuce craps.
well, benny wasn't chicken. they
didn't waste any time on him.
i tell you,
we haven't got a chance.
turn it off, bart.
you're embarrassing me
in front of the sheriff.
but, johnny, even if we
swing it, he's the president.
they'll never give up.
you don't figure that
the guys who are paying off
are just gonna let you fly away,
do you?
they'll be after you,
just like the secret service.
i thought of that too, sheriff.
it might be an internationally
embarrassing situation
if the feds happen
to catch up with us first.
so, bart, you just gotta realize
that everybody's
gonna be on your tail
from five o'clock
until the day you die.
there's a hole in your argument,
sheriff.
and what is it?
we're already wanted
for murder,
so you can only
take the gas once.
they'll get us, johnny.
they won't get us, bart.
not us.
you sure, johnny?
you leave it to me.
you're sick, man.
you're sick.
i don't like that.
don't play god
just because you've got a gun.
but, you see, sheriff,
that's the way it is.
when you've got a gun,
you are a sort of god.
if you had the gun, i'd be
the chump and you'd be the god.
the gun gives you
the power of life and death.
it's a funny sort of feeling, to
have control of life and death.
you musta had it during the war.
you could miss the man
if you had a mind to,
or you could kill him
dead in his tracks.
and that made you kind of god.
and i liked it.
without the gun, i'm nothing.
and i never had anything
before i got one.
first time i got one in my hands
and killed a man,
i got some self-respect.
i was somebody.
like this kid over here.
if that cap pistol was a real
gun and i didn't have a gun,
he'd be a kind of a god too.
and if i wanted my life, i'd
worship the ground he walks on.
and i'd pay him the half
a million dollars for my life.
because life is all i have.
but the squirt doesn't
have the gun. i have.
and i can loose the lightning.
t.v. announcer: ...inning,
the score's all tied up,
five and five.
no noise, just pictures.
announcer: ...for the first time
this season.
it's quite a ball club
out here---
pop: butterfingers.
...keep going like this, they're
going to have that pennant
two years in a row.
now we pause briefly
for a station identi--
you're wrong about god
and the guns, sheriff.
without the gun,
you would never have spit at me.
you would never
have even noticed me.
but because of the gun, you'll
remember me as long as you live.
what is it now?
they're blowing for
the 66 crossing, outside town.
all right, nobody moves.
this is it.
you, over there.
johnny, let me see once.
we're gonna do it, bart.
this is my meat.
we're gonna do it.
just to see.
return fire!
hold your fire!
oof!
pidge!
it didn't stop.
it didn't stop. it didn't stop!
oh!
no.
don't. no!
please, no.
no. no.
are you sure you're
gonna be all right, mr. benson?
oh, don't worry about me,
mr. wilson. i'll be all right.
i don't need any nursemaid.
well, we're certainly
grateful to you.
how come the train went
right through the station?
we simply canceled
the stopover.
we couldn't take a chance
on the president's safety
once it was proven
the assassins were in town.
the president went on
to los angeles.
missed his fishing, huh?
i'm afraid so.
some day, those guys are gonna
stop taking you for amateurs.
huh, mr. wilson?
i hope not.
well, thanks again, mr. benson.
oh, no.
you too, young man.
oh, that's all right.
some day, i'm gonna be
a bodyguard, just like you.
nonsense, boy. you're going
to grow up to be president.
and presidents have bodyguards.
and grandpops?
and grandpops.
especially grandpops.
ellen.
how's jud?
he didn't make it.
and slim?
critical, but they think
he'll be all right.
i guess somebody
had to make them stick.
what?
something dad said this morning.
about principles.
get in, tod.
i'll drive you home.
no, thanks. i've got
to go over to the office.
can i pick you up
for church tomorrow?
yeah. that'd be swell.
say, officer.
yeah?
could you tell me
the way to three rivers?
uh, you go down
to the first intersection,
you turn left,
it's about 60 miles.
thanks. what's this town?
suddenly.
suddenly what?
nah, that's the name.
that's a funny name for a town.
oh, i don't know.
i don't know about that.